Victor Arias Full Stack Web Developer

torvicarias@gmail.com

Cel. +57 3184229768

Envigado, Antioquia - Colombia

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Github</u>

I am a Full Stack Web Developer, and also an accountant. I have experience working with NodeJS, React, Redux, SQL, among other technologies. For the last six years I worked as a high school math teacher, which gave me the chance to improve my critical thinking skills as well as my organizational and planning skills. I am patient, flexible and creative.

TECHNOLOGIES

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, Material UI, React, Redux, NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Scrum, Canva, Trello, Slack, Google Workspace, Git and GitHub

PROJECTS

Full Stack Web Developer - Hexatech (e-commerce)

Henry Bootcamp

- Designed and developed an e-commerce app, which included: content management capabilities, authentication, a shopping cart, a checkout, responsive design, among others.
- Technologies used: React, Redux, Bootstrap, NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL and Sequelize.
 App link

Full Stack Web Developer - Dogs App

Henry Bootcamp

- Designed and developed an app about dogs, which included: search, filter, sort and create functions.
- Technologies used: React, Redux, CSS, NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL and Sequelize.
 App link

Front End Web Developer - Loan Calculator

Personal Project

- Designed and developed a loan calculator app, which included: an amortization schedule for fixed/variable payment loans.
- Technologies used: React and Material UI.
 App link

EXPERIENCE

High School Math Teacher

Aug. 2016 - Jun. 2022

Fundación Liceo Inglés, Pereira, Colombia.

- Designed and instructed high school mathematics classes, grades 10 through 12.
- Algebra, Trigonometry, Precalculus, Calculus and Statistics.

Front End Web Developer

Oct. 2021 - Nov. 2021

BOs Ingeniería e Innovación SAS, Pereira, Colombia.

Developed digital learning objects using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and Javascript.

Math Teacher Feb. 2016 - Nov. 2016

Politécnico Metropolitano Centro Occidente SAS, Pereira, Colombia.

 Designed and instructed mathematics and financial mathematics classes for undergraduate students pursuing technical degrees.

Accounting Bookkeeper

Feb. 2014 - Feb. 2015

Anestesiarte SAS, Pereira, Colombia.

• Bookkeeping, reconciliation and payroll preparation.

EDUCATION

- Full Stack Web Developer. Henry Bootcamp. 2022.
- Full Stack Web Developer. Misión TIC. 2021.
- Postgraduate Degree in Finance. Universidad Católica de Pereira. 2015 2016.
- Certified Public Accountant. Universidad Libre. 2009 2014.

COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Foundations: Data, Data, Everywhere. Coursera. 2021.
- Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python). Coursera. 2021.
- Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate SFPC. CertiProf. 2021.
- 18.01x Single Variable Calculus, MITx on edX. 2021.
- Crash Course on Python, Coursera, 2021.
- Google Certified Educator Level 2, Google for Education, 2020.
- Google Certified Educator Level 1, Google for Education, 2019.

LANGUAGES

English C2 - Proficient.